Hi!
My name is Ashley Ludman from Seaside Yoga.
So, the question is, what does yoga do for the body?
A lot of times we think of yoga as being a tool to help us gain flexibility, and many people that I meet on the street and talk to about yoga, they think that they cannot do yoga because they are not flexible enough.
Well, in essence they are strong, so strength and flexibility are a great marriage for any type of yoga posture.
So, physically, the postures or the Asanas that we perform in a yoga class on a yoga mat, help us to find that balance within.
When you are in a new posture, you might start to be aware of your legs.
You might start to be more aware of your hips, more aware of how your core supports you.
How your shoulders need to open up so that you can gain more breathe within your lungs.
So, yoga affects the body in the external form, but also internally.
It affects our physiological systems.
When we are bending forward in Forward Bends, we are creating an internal massage to our digestive system.
When we are going into Spinal Twist, we are creating a massaging action for the intervertebral joints.
So in essence, our yoga practice benefits our physical body, not just in our strength and our flexibility, but it also benefits our internal organ functions.
It affects brain control and mindfulness of stress reduction.
So, it affects our body in so many different ways and I hope you find the great affects and I hope your body enjoys your yoga practice.